Finding aid to Alumnae Oral History Project collection CA.MS.00301
Smith College Archives
- Alumnae Oral History Project interviews (2015), Accession 2016-A-0001
  - Laura Goodman Jacobs (Class of 1965) interviewed by Hana Sarfan, 2015 May 15; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Laura Jacobs discusses her move from New York City to Northampton. She discusses the social and academic difficulties she faced during the transition and recalls the relationships she formed with her roommate and fellow students who helped her during that adjustment period. She discusses her house community, the roles that house mothers played within that community, as well as her experience as a Jewish woman at Smith and one of two women majoring in physics.
    - Video interview with Laura Goodman Jacobs
    - Transcript of interview with Laura Goodman Jacobs (Box 13)
  - Ja'Milla CK Lomas (Class of 2000) interviewed by Hana Sarfan, 2015 May 22; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    Ja'Milla Lomas begins her interview recounting her accidental introduction to Smith by way of Ruth Simmons, who visited her high school in Houston, Texas. She details her involvement in student government, close relationships with staff and faculty and how her close knit house community was interrupted by a racist incident during her first semester. Lomas explains how the incident affected the remainder of her Smith experience and compares and contrasts this with her Junior Year Away experience at Howard University. She describes the benefits and opportunities afforded her by her Smith network, after college, particularly during the 2007-2008 recession, and credits them with encouraging her to pursue her passion.
    - Video interview with Ja'Milla CK Lomas
    - Transcript of interview with Ja'Milla CK Lomas (Box 13)
  - Heather Neal (AC 2005) interviewed by Tanya Pearson, 2015 May 23; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview Heather Neal, recounts her dissatisfaction with her work in advertising, subsequent career change and return to community college where she learned about the Ada Comstock Scholars program at Smith. She recalls navigating campus life as a non-traditional student and her involvement in the Ada cabinet and extracurricular activities. Neal also describes finding feminism when she came out and how her Smith experience expanded on that prior knowledge and how higher education fosters female autonomy at any age.
    - Video interview with Heather Neal
    - Transcript of interview with Heather Neal (Box 13)
  - Kathleen Banks Nutter (AC 1990) interviewed by Izzy Levy, 2015 May 22; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Kathleen Banks Nutter discusses how marriage and motherhood delayed her college education until her early 30s. She details her unique undergrad experience as a mother of young children, commuting to campus and scheduling classes around her husband's work schedule. Banks Nutter also talks about beneficial connections and opportunities she made at Smith and her 25 year career as accessioning archivist at the Sophia Smith Collection.
    - Video interview with Kathleen Banks Nutter
    - Transcript of interview with Kathleen Banks Nutter (Box 13)
  - Kimberly Roberts (Class of 1975) interviewed by Izzy Levy, 2015 May 15; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    - Video interview with Kimberly Roberts
    - Transcript of interview with Kimberly Roberts (Box 13)
  - Kathryn "Kathy" Rodgers (Class of 1970) interviewed by Hana Sarfan, 2015 May 22; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Kathy Rodgers recalls her decision to apply to Smith and desire for a college rather than university experience. She discusses her transition from a public high school and the challenges she faced, academically. Rodgers details her house community, including the chores and household duties that students were expected to carry out. She also describes the internal changes that were occurring on campus in the midst of the Civil Rights Movement and Vietnam War.
    - Video interview with Kathryn "Kathy" Rodgers
    - Transcript of interview with Kathryn "Kathy" Rodgers (Box 13)
  - Laura Scandalis (AC 2006) interviewed by Hana Sarfan, 2015 May 22; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Laura Scandalis describes her introduction to Smith as a young mother and paralegal and how she was able to navigate student life and balance her academics while parenting a young child. She talks about the support system that exists among Adas and her struggle to find her place within the larger student body. Scandalis details the importance of networking and how her Smith connections have continued to benefit her post-graduation.
    - Video interview with Laura Scandalis
    - Transcript of interview with Laura Scandalis (Box 13)
  - Mary Rose Caldwell Schlatter (Class of 1955) interviewed by Tanya Pearson, 2015 May 22; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Mary Rose "Pattee" Caldwell Schlatter discusses how her decision to attend Smith was greatly influenced by her mother's experience at the college. She details her mother's early college life and compares and contrasts their personal experiences. Schlatter details her academic choices and major as well as the social and dating life on campus in the 1950s. She discusses her post-Smith career, marriage and children, as well as her volunteer work and current activism.
    - Video interview with Mary Rose Caldwell Schlatter
    - Transcript of interview with Mary Rose Caldwell Schlatter (Box 13)
  - Faith Sullivan (AC 2002) interviewed by Tanya Pearson, 2015 May 23; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    Faith Sullivan begins her interview discussing how she left nursing school at 19 to get married and start a family and how she eventually found her way to community college when her youngest child was in high school. Sullivan describes how the opportunity to attend Smith came about and how she was able to balance home, career and academic life as a non-traditional student. She attributes her courage and confidence to her Smith education, characteristics that enabled her to finish graduate school despite the death of her son, Tony. Sullivan discusses her time at Harvard Divinty and her current career in psychotherapy.
    - Video interview with Faith Sullivan
    - Transcript of interview with Faith Sullivan (Box 13)
  - Katherine Swibold (Class of 1982) and Hannah Becker (Class of 2015) interviewed by Tanya Pearson, 2015 May 15; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Katherine Swibold and her daughter Hannah Becker recall their introductions to Smith and undergrad experiences. They tell personal stories about their study abroad experiences and compare and contrast the evolution of the campus, student body and political and social climates. Swibold discusses the importance of utilizing the Smith network after graduation and Becker discusses her plans for the future and how her Smith education has prepared her it.
    - Video interview with Katherine Swibold and Hannah Becker
    - Transcript of interview with Katherine Swibold and Hannah Becker (Box 13)
  - Jessie Taylor (Class of 2010) interviewed by Izzy Levy, 2015 May 23; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Jessie Taylor describes her Smith experience as 'coming home' and details the sense of community and diversity found on campus upon her arrival in 2005. She also discusses political division among students during the Bush administration and Iraq War as well as the growing presence of trans and genderqueer students on campus. She discusses being raised as an atheist and majoring in religion as well as how her major applies to her present career in IT.
    - Video interview with Jessie Taylor
    - Transcript of interview with Jessie Taylor (Box 13)
  - Sydney Waller (Class of 1970) interviewed by Izzy Levy, 2015 May 23; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Sydney Waller discusses her involvement in the Students for a Democratic Society and their activism in response to the Vietnam War. She talks about the countercultural movement, Free University, in Northampton at the time, her active participation within the group and the climate on the Smith campus during the Civil Rights Movement and assassinations of Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. and Bobby Kennedy. Waller comments on the administration's response to student protests and discusses her post Smith activist work.
    - Video interview with Sydney Waller
    - Transcript of interview with Sydney Waller (Box 13)
  - Judy Clymer Welles (Class of 1965) interviewed by Izzy Levy, 2015 May 15; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Judy Clymer Welles discusses poignant experiences as a freshman at Smith, student activism and political climate on campus during the Civil Rights movement. She speaks candidly about the house communities, rules and regulations during that time period, the strict honor code as well as social life and extracurricular activities. In closing Welles comments on the physical changes on campus as well the evolution of academics and class offerings.
    - Video interview with Judy Clymer Welles
    - Transcript of interview with Judy Clymer Welles (Box 13)
  - Wendy Welsh (AC 1995) interviewed by Hana Sarfan, 2015 May 23; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Wendy Welsh discusses how she left a career in insurance in order to finish her education at Smith. She talks about her academic life and coursework, the male dominated computer science major and compares and contrasts her classroom experiences at Smith and UMass. She credits specific Smith professors with instilling confidence and details life after Smith and how her Smith education has benefited her personally and professionally.
    - Video interview with Wendy Welsh
    - Transcript of interview with Wendy Welsh (Box 13)
  - Devon Wilson-Hill (Class of 2005) interviewed by Izzy Levy, 2015 May 16; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    Devon Wilson-Hill recounts how her decision to attend Smith was cemented after a last minute visit to the campus. She discusses the close knit Hubbard House community and the close friendships she made as a result. Wilson-Hill also talks about her involvement in the Radical Cheerleaders, student response to racist incidences on campus and the September 11th attacks, and details a trip with fellow students to Washington, D.C. to participate in a march on Washington, protesting the war in Iraq. In closing, she considers the influence Smith continues to have on her life and career.
    - Video interview with Devon Wilson-Hill
    - Transcript of interview with Devon Wilson-Hill (Box 13)
  - Sarah Winawer Wetzel (Class of 2005) interviewed by Hana Sarfan, 2015 May 15; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Sarah Winawer-Wetzel describes her house community and social life during her first semester at Smith. She details campus response to the attacks on September 11th and the divisiveness that resulted from the amending of the student constitution to include gender neutral pronouns. Winawer-Wetzler discusses personal challenges and how her Smith career continues to influence her personal and professional life.
    - Video interview with Sarah Winawer Wetzel
    - Transcript of interview with Sarah Winawer Wetzel (Box 13)
  - Elinor Yahm (Class of 1965) interviewed by Hana Sarfan, 2015 May 16; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Elinor Yahm discusses her difficult transition into the Smith community as a young Jewish woman from New York. She talks about her major in political science and how it influenced her post Smith work during the Women's Movement. Yahm recalls the expectations placed on students and the affect it had on her academically as well as the pros and cons of attending a single sex institution.
    - Video interview with Elinor Yahm
    - Transcript of interview with Elinor Yahm (Box 13)
- Alumnae Oral History Project interviews (2016), Accession 2016-A-0025
  - Neelum Amin (Class of 1986) interviewed by Rebecca York, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Neelum Amin talks about her introduction to Smith, taking advantage of a liberal arts education, house community, and Smith's social and political climate during the 80s. Amin lived in both Washburn and Talbot House, and was a member of the International Students' Organization. Since graduation Amin has stayed connected to the Smith community through participation in the Smith Clubs.
    - Video interview with Neelum Amin
    - Transcript of interview with Neelum Amin (Box 14)
  - Mariquita Anderson (Class of 1986) interviewed by Rebecca York, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Mariquita Anderson talks about her introduction to Smith through the Bridge Program. Anderson also looks back on her community in Gillett House, the sing a long's around the house piano, and engaging conversations over Friday tea. Anderson reflects on the position of Asian American students in conversations of race, and the process of self-discovery at Smith and beyond.
    - Video interview with Mariquita Anderson
    - Transcript of interview with Mariquita Anderson (Box 14)
  - Kirstin Gamble Bridier (Class of 1996) interviewed by Milada Cook, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In her interview, Kirstin Bridier remembers her time in Emerson House and talks about favorite house traditions like convocation, and Medieval Banquet. An English major with an interest in vocal performance, she talks about the influence professors in both departments had on her time at Smith. Bridier also recounts her work in the Smith College Archives.
    - Video interview with Kirstin Gamble Bridier
    - Transcript of interview with Kirstin Gamble Bridier (Box 14)
  - Jenna Caggiano (Class of 1996) interviewed by Rebecca York, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Jenna Caggiano remembers favorite Emerson house traditions like Medieval Banquet, Thursday dinners, and Saturday teas, and the important role that professors played in making these events special. She also talks about mentors found in the Italian department who played an integral role in her Smith career. Now a teacher herself, Caggiano makes sure to emphasize Smith, and women's education to her students.
    - Video interview with Jenna Caggiano
    - Transcript of interview with Jenna Caggiano (Box 14)
  - Neelofer Chaudry (Class of 1996) and Mahima Joishy (Class of 1996) interviewed by Milada Cook, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, best friends, Mahima Joishy and Neelofer Chaudry look back on how they met, and how their friendship influenced their time at Smith. Having both lived in Wilder house, Joishy and Chaudry recount their favorite Wilder cheers and traditions. Joishy and Chaudry were also involved in Ekta, the South Asian Students' Association.
    - Video interview with Neelofer Chaudry and Mahima Joishy
    - Transcript of interview with Neelofer Chaudry and Mahima Joishy (Box 14)
  - Jessica Chestnutt (Class of 2006) and Natalie Sauro (Class of 2006) interviewed by Sonia Lawrence, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Jessica Chestnutt and Natalie Sauro talk about their time at Smith, including how they met, the influence of feminism on campus culture, and favorite Smith traditions. Chestnutt was a member of Ziskind House and Sessions Annex, while Sauro lived in Albright House.
    - Video interview with Jessica Chestnutt and Natalie Sauro
    - Transcript of interview with Jessica Chestnutt and Natalie Sauro (Box 14)
  - Mary "Kye" Cochran (Class of 1966) interviewed by Milada Cook, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Kye Cochran reflects on her life after Smith. Having been at Smith for a year, Cochran decided to leave, going on to travel the world with a marine biologist. Cochran talks about her travels as well as starting the Alternative Energy Resources Organization, and the conception of her co-op, Local Energy and Food, in White River, Montana.
    - Video interview with Mary "Kye" Cochran
    - Transcript of interview with Mary "Kye" Cochran (Box 14)
  - Deborah Davis (Class of 1976) interviewed by Milada Cook, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Deborah Davis remembers finding community at Smith, both in Lawrence House and beyond. She also talks about how she came to double major in Molecular Biology and English, while still having time to found the Smith Prank Committee.
    - Video interview with Deborah Davis
    - Transcript of interview with Deborah Davis (Box 14)
  - Joanna DeJesus (Class of 1986) interviewed by Sonia Lawrence, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Joanna De Jesus reflects on life at Smith as an international student, and on how she found community on campus. De Jesus talks about her involvement with the Student Government Association, as well as writing for The Sophian. De Jesus also remembers what it was like being the President of the Nosotras Association.
    - Video interview with Joanna DeJesus
    - Transcript of interview with Joanna DeJesus (Box 14)
  - Harriett Destler (Class of 1961) interviewed by Milada Cook, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Harriet Destler talks about Smith's horse-back riding team, her History major, and engaging in political leadership on campus. Destler recounts a number of political actions that she both led and participated in during her tenure at Smith. Destler jokes about her inability to learn languages, and discusses skills she learned at Smith that have served her well in her work at both the US Agency for International Development and beyond.
    - Video interview with Harriett Destler
    - Transcript of interview with Harriett Destler (Box 14)
  - Iris González (Class of 2011) interviewed by Sunny Lawrence, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Iris González remembers her transition to Smith, and finding community within Nosotras and the Black Students' Alliance. González looks back on the political climate on campus and the reactions of various Smith groups and organizations. González also talks about transitioning between houses, and the administrators and staff who helped make Smith feel like home.
    - Video interview with Iris González
    - Transcript of interview with Iris González (Box 14)
  - Robin Lee Greiner (Class of 1986) interviewed by Milada Cook, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Robin Greiner talks about the important role that friendship played in shaping her time at Smith. She reflects on Smith as a feminist and activist driven space, and the tensions that arose from that. Greiner participated in Smith's Geneva study abroad program, and was a coxswain for the Smith College Crew Team.
    - Video interview with Robin Lee Greiner
    - Transcript of interview with Robin Lee Greiner (Box 14)
  - Francesca Grifo (Class of 1981) interviewed by Rebecca York, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Francesca Grifo talks about how she chose to major in Biology, found mentors in the department, and found community on the Crew team. She also looks back on her time as Head Resident of Dawes House. Grifo delves into her current work at the Environmental Protection Agency, and tells the story of how she got there.
    - Video interview with Francesca Grifo
    - Transcript of interview with Francesca Grifo (Box 14)
  - Daryl Maslow Hafter (Class of 1956) interviewed by Sunny Lawrence, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Daryl Maslow Hafter talks about her religious background and finding a community at Smith. Hafter also reflects on favorite campus traditions, like going to Yale for Mountain Day. Hafter talks about her passion she developed at Smith for eighteenth-century French history, which she continued to study in graduate school.
    - Video interview with Daryl Maslow Hafter
    - Transcript of interview with Daryl Maslow Hafter (Box 14)
  - Sabine Jean (Class of 2011) interviewed by Milada Cook, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Sabine Jean talks about being President of the Student Government Association, and acting as an intermediary between students and administrators. A Government and Africana Studies major, Jean was also involved with the BSA, and co-founded the Smith Law Society.
    - Video interview with Sabine Jean
    - Transcript of interview with Sabine Jean (Box 14)
  - Linda S. Kaufman (Class of 1956) interviewed by Sunny Lawrence, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Linda Kaufman remembers her transition to Smith from a rigorous independent high school. She talks about her experience as a history major, her time in different houses, serving as the treasurer of the student council, and the image of a "typical Smithie." A high school history teacher, Kaufman reflects on being the voice for women and girls at her schools, a role that is deeply influenced by her time at Smith.
    - Video interview with Linda S. Kaufman
    - Transcript of interview with Linda S. Kaufman (Box 14)
  - Catherine Kay (Class of 1981) interviewed by Rebecca York, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Catherine (Cathy) Kay talks about the powerful influence the Smith College Music Department had on her life, both as a student, and beyond. Kay was a History major, but found community and friendship through her participation in the Smith College Choirs as a singer and accompanist. Kay also remembers her favorite traditions of Washburn House.
    - Video interview with Catherine Kay
    - Transcript of interview with Catherine Kay (Box 14)
  - Elizabeth Kessler (Class of 1991) interviewed by Rebecca York, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Elizabeth (Liza) Kessler recounts her introduction to Smith as a sophomore transfer student from Reed College. She talks about her time as a Head Resident, as well as her work with the Racism and Cultural Awareness panel and the Women's Resource Center. Kessler also reflects on her life after Smith, her surprising career trajectory, and what it takes to land on your feet.
    - Video interview with Elizabeth Kessler
    - Transcript of interview with Elizabeth Kessler (Box 14)
  - Brandy King (Class of 2001) interviewed by Rebecca York, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Brandy King talks about transferring to Smith as a junior, the Women and Gender Studies Major, and Wilder House traditions. King also remembers her work as a Gold Key Guide for the college, and her work as a Resident Coordinator post-graduation.
    - Video interview with Brandy King
    - Transcript of interview with Brandy King (Box 14)
  - Ruth "Boots" Matthews Leiter (Class of 1951) interviewed by Sonia Lawrence, 2016 May; 1 oral histories (transcript and video)
    In this interview, Ruth "Boots" Leiter traces her time at Smith through her relationship with the French department. Having lived in the French house, and participated heavily in the department, her knowledge of the language has continued to serve Leiter to this day. The interview also highlights the social and political scenes at Smith during the late 1940s and early 1950s.
    - Video interview with Ruth "Boots" Matthews Leiter
    - Transcript of interview with Ruth "Boots" Matthews Leider (Box 14)